liveoffice.com 2012-10-22

# LiveOffice Privacy Statement | LiveOffice

LiveOffice, LLC (“LiveOffice” or the “Company”) is committed to protecting the privacy of your information. This Privacy Statement describes LiveOffice’s information practices. LiveOffice provides managed email archiving, email compliance, email discovery, email continuity, financial websites and Exchange hosting solutions.

LiveOffice complies with the US-EU Safe Harbor Framework and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland.  LiveOffice has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification page, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

In compliance with the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, LiveOffice commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact LiveOffice at [support@liveoffice.com](mailto:support@liveoffice.com).

LiveOffice has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by LiveOffice, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at [www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints ](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints%20)for more information and to file a complaint.

## 1\. Web Sites Covered

This Privacy Statement covers the information practices of Web sites that link to this Privacy Statement: [http://www.liveoffice.com](http://www.liveoffice.com/ "LiveOffice.com"); [http://www.advisormail.net](http://www.advisormail.net/ "AdvisorMail.net"); and[http://www.advisorsquare.com](http://www.advisorsquare.com/ "AdvisorSquare.com") (collectively referred to as “liveoffice.coms Web sites” or “the Company’s Web sites”). LiveOffice.com’s Web sites may contain links to other Web sites. LiveOffice is not responsible for the information practices or the content of such other Web sites. LiveOffice encourages you to review the privacy statements of other Web sites to understand their information practices.

## 2\. Personal Information Collected

LiveOffice offers a variety of services which include managed email archiving, email compliance, email discovery, email continuity, financial websites and Exchange hosting solutions collectively referred to as the “Service.” LiveOffice collects information from individuals who visit the Company’s Web sites (“Visitors”) and individuals who register to use the Service (“Customers”).

When expressing an interest in obtaining additional information about the Service or registering to use the Service, LiveOffice requires you to provide the Company with contact information, such as name, company name, address, phone number, and email address (“Required Contact Information”). When purchasing the Service, LiveOffice requires you to provide the Company with financial qualification and billing information, such as billing name and address, credit card number, and the number of employees within the organization that will be using the Service (“Billing Information”). LiveOffice may also ask you to provide additional information, such as company annual revenues, number of employees, or industry (“Optional Information”). Required Contact Information, Billing Information, and Optional Information are referred to collectively as “Customer-Visitor Information.”

As you navigate the Company’s Web sites, LiveOffice may also collect information through the use of commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons (“Web Site Navigational Information”). Web Site Navigational Information includes standard information from your Web browser (such as browser type and browser language), your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the actions you take on the Company’s Web sites (such as the Web pages viewed and the links clicked).

## 3\. Use of Information Collected

The Company uses Customer-Visitor Information to perform the services requested. For example, if you fill out a “Contact Me” Web form, the Company will use the information provided to contact you about your interest in the requested services.

The Company may also use Customer-Visitor Information for marketing purposes. For example, the Company may use information you provide to contact you to further discuss your interest in LiveOffice, LiveOffice services, and to send you information regarding the Company and its partners, such as information about promotions or events.

LiveOffice uses credit card information solely to check the financial qualifications of prospective Customers and to collect payment for the Service.

LiveOffice uses Web Site Navigational Information to operate and improve the Company’s Web sites. The Company may also use Web Site Navigational Information in combination with Customer-Visitor Information to provide personalized information about the Company.

## 4\. Public Forums, Refer a Friend, and Customer Testimonials

LiveOffice may provide bulletin boards, blogs, or chat rooms on the Company’s Web sites and/or third party Web sites such as Facebook and Twitter. Any personally identifiable information you choose to submit in such a forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these forums, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. LiveOffice is not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

Customers and Visitors may elect to use LiveOffice’s referral service to inform colleagues about the Company’s Web sites or LiveOffice’s services. When using the referral service, the Company requests the colleague’s name and email address. LiveOffice will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Company’s Web sites. LiveOffice does not store this information.

LiveOffice posts a list of Customers and testimonials on the Company’s Web sites that contain information such as Customer names and titles. LiveOffice obtains the consent of each Customer prior to posting any information on such a list or posting testimonials.

## 5\. Web Site Navigational Information

LiveOffice uses commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons, to collect information as you navigate the Company’s Web sites (“Web Site Navigational Information”). This section describes the types of Web Site Navigational Information the Company may collect and how the Company may use this information.

### Cookies

LiveOffice uses cookies to make interactions with the Company’s Web sites easy and meaningful. When you visit one of the Company’s Web sites, LiveOffice’s servers send a cookie to your computer. Standing alone, cookies do not personally identify you. They merely recognize your Web browser. Unless you choose to identify yourself to LiveOffice, either by responding to a promotional offer, opening an account, or filling out a Web form (such as a “Contact Me” or a “14 Day Free Trial” Web form), you remain anonymous to the Company.

There are two types of cookies: session-based and persistent-based. Session cookies exist only during one session. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser software or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you close your browser or turn off your computer.

If you have chosen to identify yourself to LiveOffice, the Company uses session cookies containing information to allow the Company to uniquely identify you. Each time you log into the Service, a session cookie containing a unique identifier that is tied to your account is placed in your browser. These session cookies allow the Company to uniquely identify you when you are logged into the Service and to process your online transactions and requests. Session cookies are required to use the Service.

LiveOffice uses persistent cookies that only the Company can read and use to identify browsers that have previously visited the Company’s Web sites. When you purchase the Service or provide the Company with personal information, a unique identifier is assigned you. This unique identifier is associated with a persistent cookie that the Company places on your Web browser. The Company is especially careful about the security and confidentiality of the information stored in persistent cookies. For example, the Company does not store account numbers or passwords in persistent cookies. If you disable your Web browser’s ability to accept cookies, you will be able to navigate the Company’s Web sites, but you will not be able to successfully use the Service. LiveOffice may use information from session and persistent cookies in combination with Customer-Visitor Information to provide you with information about the Company and the Service.

### Web Beacons

LiveOffice uses Web beacons alone or in conjunction with cookies to compile information about Customers and Visitors’ usage of the Company’s Web sites and interaction with emails from the Company. Web beacons are clear electronic images that can recognize certain types of information on your computer, such as cookies, when you viewed a particular Web site tied to the Web beacon, and a description of a Web site tied to the Web beacon. For example, LiveOffice may place Web beacons in marketing emails that notify the Company when you click on a link in the email that directs you to one of the Company’s Web sites. LiveOffice uses Web beacons to operate and improve the Company’s Web sites and email communications. LiveOffice.com may use information from Web beacons in combination with Customer-Visitor Information to provide you with information about the Company and the Service.

### IP Addresses

When you visit LiveOffice Web sites, the Company collects your Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses to track and aggregate non-personally identifiable information. For example, LiveOffice uses IP addresses to monitor the regions from which Customers and Visitors navigate the Company’s Web sites.

LiveOffice also collects IP addresses from Customers whey they log into the Service as part of the Company’s “Identity Confirmation” and “IP Range Restrictions” security features.

### Third Party Cookies

From time-to-time, LiveOffice engages third parties to track and analyze non-personally identifiable usage and volume statistical information from individuals who visit the Company’s Web sites. LiveOffice may also use other third-party cookies to track the performance of Company advertisements. The information provided to third parties does not include personal information, but this information may be re-associated with personal information after the Company receives it. This Privacy Statement does not cover the use of third party cookies.

## 6\. Sharing of Information Collected

LiveOffice may share Customer-Visitor Information with the Company’s agents, contractors or partners in connection with services that these individuals or entities perform for, or with, LiveOffice. These agents, contractors or partners are restricted from using Customer-Visitor Information in any way other than to provide services for LiveOffice, or services for the collaboration in which they and the Company are engaged (for example, some of our products are developed and marketed through joint agreements with other companies). LiveOffice may also share Customer-Visitor Information with the Company’s agents, contractors or partners to ensure the quality of information provided. LiveOffice does not share, sell, rent, or trade personally identifiable information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

LiveOffice uses a third-party intermediary to manage credit card processing. This intermediary is not permitted to store, retain, or use Billing Information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on the Company’s behalf.

LiveOffice reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable information of the Company’s Customers or Visitors if required by law or if the Company reasonably believes that disclosure is necessary to protect the Company’s rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process.

## 7\. Communications Preferences

LiveOffice offers Customers and Visitors who provide contact information a means to choose how the Company uses the information provided. You may manage your receipt of marketing and non-transactional communications by sending an email to[privacy@liveoffice.com](mailto:privacy@liveoffice.com?subject=Privacy:%20Manage%20Communications "\[GMCP\] Compose a new mail to privacy@liveoffice.com") or by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of the Company’s marketing emails. Customers cannot opt out of receiving transactional emails related to their account with LiveOffice or the Service.

## 8\. Correcting and Updating Your Information

To update a user profile, Customers can login into their Administrative Console with their username and password and can edit, add, modify and delete individual users. To update Billing Information or have your registration information deleted, please email [billing@liveoffice.com](mailto:billing@liveoffice.com?subject=Privacy:%20Update%20Billing "\[GMCP\] Compose a new mail to billing@liveoffice.com") or call (800) 251-3863, option #3. To discontinue your account and have information you maintained in the Service returned to you, please email [support@liveoffice.com](mailto:support@liveoffice.com?subject=Privacy:%20Discontinue "\[GMCP\] Compose a new mail to support@liveoffice.com"). Requests to access, change, or delete your information will be handled within 30 days unless a different term is mutually negotiated. Nothing in this Privacy Statement should be interpreted to allow the unilateral termination or modification of any agreement, or any term thereof, between LiveOffice and a Customer.

## 9\. Customer Data

LiveOffice Customers use the Service to host or store email, data and information (“Customer Data”). LiveOffice may share Customer Data with agents, contractors or partners in connection with the provision of the Service to Customers. These agents, contractors or partners are restricted from using Customer Data in any way other than to provide the Service. LiveOffice will not review, share, distribute, or reference any such Customer Data except if expressly provided in a written agreement between LiveOffice and Customer or as may be required by law. Customers are responsible for maintaining the security and confidentiality of their LiveOffice usernames and passwords.

## 10\. Security

LiveOffice uses robust security measures to protect Customer Data from unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and help ensure the appropriate use of Customer Data. When the Service is accessed using Internet Explorer version 6.0 or later, Secure Socket Layer (“SSL”) technology protects Customer Data using both server authentication and data encryption. These technologies help ensure that Customer Data is safe, secure, and only available to the Customer to whom the information belongs and those to whom the Customer has granted access. LiveOffice also implements an advanced security method based on dynamic data and encoded session identifications, and the Company hosts its Web sites in a secure server environment that uses firewalls and other advanced technology to prevent interference or access from outside intruders. LiveOffice also offers enhanced security features within the Service that permit Customers to configure security settings to the level they deem necessary.

Because the Company uses the Service to maintain Customer-Visitor Information, this information is secured in the same manner as described above for Customer Data.

## 11\. LiveOffice’s Policy Toward Children

The Company’s Web site are not directed to children under 18. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided LiveOffice with personal or contact information without their consent, he or she should contact the Company at[privacy@LiveOffice.com](mailto:privacy@liveoffice.com?subject=Privacy:%20Policy%20Toward%20Children "\[GMCP\] Compose a new mail to privacy@LiveOffice.com"). If LiveOffice become aware that a child under 13 has provided the Company with personal information, LiveOffice will delete such information from the Company’s files.

## 12\. Changes to this Privacy Statement

LiveOffice reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement. LiveOffice will provide notification of the material changes to this Privacy Statement through the Company’s Web sites at least thirty (30) business days prior to the change taking effect.

## 13\. Contacting Us

Questions regarding this Privacy Statement or the information practices of the Company’s Web sites should be emailed to [privacy@liveoffice.com](mailto:privacy@liveoffice.com?subject=Privacy:%20Questions "\[GMCP\] Compose a new mail to privacy@liveoffice.com") or by mailing LiveOffice, LLC, Attn: Privacy, 2780 Skypark Drive, Suite 300, Torrance, CA 90505.
